<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fabrik</title>
    <link>https://fabrik.red/</link>
    <description>Recent content on fabrik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 15:30:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fabrik.red/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the image (disk.raw)</title>
      <link>https://fabrik.red/post/creating-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 15:30:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fabrik.red/post/creating-the-image/</guid>
      <description>Creating the image (disk.raw) The fastest way of doing this (less than 1 hour &amp;ldquo;7min&amp;rdquo;) is to use AWS and chose the c4.8xlarge instance, at the moment of writhing this, is an instance with 36 vCPU / 60 RAM, the important thing to check for is the amount of cores not really the memory. After finishing building, stop or terminate the build instance, mainly because is a very expensive and in best scenario you just want to do all this in less than 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>https://fabrik.red/post/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 10:06:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fabrik.red/post/test/</guid>
      <description>DRAFT Download the image: disk.tar.gz
The image can be uploaded directly to AWS, Google compute engine or to test it within Virtualbox need to convert it to VDI format:
$ VBoxManage convertfromraw disk.raw ec2.vdi --format VDI  The image size is 2GB, once the image is in VDI format it can be resized:
$ VBoxManage modifyhd ec2.vdi --resize 20480   20480 will create a 20GB disk
 Once the image has been booted it can be resized within zfs: https://nbari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Fabrik</title>
      <link>https://fabrik.red/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:51:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fabrik.red/about/</guid>
      <description>What is Fabrik ? A tool for creating and managing jails.
Why ? FreeBSD is a beast. Unfortunately few are capable of taking advantage all the benefits and capabilities available within it.
It is a fact that for having a proper setup some work needs to be done, you don&amp;rsquo;t get diamonds by just putting carbon in the microwave and wait for a couple of minutes.
The idea behind Fabrik is to simplify the initial/bootstrap work (custom kernel + ZFS) and come with a ready to work image that can be used out of the box and create jails on demand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>